Finding Aid for Peter Pollack papers, 1965-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project Files
  - Pfizer Campus Projects
    - Drawings and Plans
      - Pfizer
        - Building 35
          - Storm Water Infrastructure September 16, 2004 (Tube 33)
          - Sitework Bid Package October 10, 2005 (Tube 33)
        - Building 85 -- Fire Pump House and Emergency Services
          - Plans Submitted for PUD Site Plan April 9, 2003 (Tube 34)
          - Building 85 and Building 75 -- Submitted for PUD Site Plan Construction Approval September 25, 2003 (Tube 34)
        - Building 910 Site Demolition and Meadow Restoration -- Issued for Bidding March 17, 2008 (Tube 35)
        - Campus Base Maps 2000 (Tube 35)
        - Guard Kiosk
          - Plans, 5 March 2002 (Tube 35)
          - Plans Issued for Construction October 5, 2004 (Tube 35)
        - Huron Parkway Reconstruction Planting Plan September 3, 2004 (Tube 36)
        - Huron Parkway Site Improvements -- Issued for Design Development Owner Review December 14, 2006 (Tube 36)
        - Master Plan
          - Preliminary Framework Diagrams November 2002 (Tube 36)
          - Sketches (Tube 36)
          - Submitted for PUD November 26, 2001 (Tube 37)
          - Traffic Study -- Proposed Changes January 15, 2002 (Tube 37)
          - Miscellaneous Plans and Sketches (Tube 37)
        - Planting Enhancements
          - Issued for Construction September 11, 2000 (Tube 37)
          - Phase II April 11, 2001 (Tube 37)
        - Prairie Conversion
          - Issued for Bidding October 28, 2002 (Tube 37)
          - Sketches October 7, 2002 (Tube 37)
        - Southwest Campus Site Restoration -- Check Set July 9, 2006 (Tube 38)
        - Miscellaneous Plans and Drawings (Tube 38)
  - Other Michigan Projects
    The Other Michigan Projects (4.5 linear feet, 13 tubes, 1 folder) subseries contains correspondence, working files, press clippings, minutes, permit applications, sketches, drawings, and plans relating to various Pollack projects in Michigan. These projects include Charlevoix, the Huron River Bikeway Study, the Huron-Whittaker Corridor Study, Independence Lake Park, and the Pere Marquette Rail Trail.
    - Textual Files
      - Charlevoix -- East Park and Marina Improvements
        - Agreement for parks project 2001 (Box 21)
        - Bid period Addendum 2 (Box 21)
        - Chronological File
          - Marina
            - May-July, 2002 (Box 21)
            - August-October, 2002 (Box 21)
          - Park
            - June 2001-June 2002 (Box 21)
            - July-September, 2002 (Box 21)
        - Clippings, 2 folders (Box 21)
        - Conference facility 2003 (Box 21)
        - Correspondence
          - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 21)
          - Park and Landslide facilities 2003 (Box 21)
        - Cost estimates (Box 22)
        - Existing Conditions 2002 (Box 22)
        - Meeting minutes 2006 (Box 22)
        - Park plan and notes 2002-2003 (Box 22)
        - Photographs -- Existing conditions 2001, color (Box 22)
        - Plan merger 2002-2003 (Box 22)
        - Project meeting notes (Box 22)
        - Public meetings (Box 22)
        - Sketches 2004 (Box 22)
        - Waterways Commission information (Box 22)
      - Huron River Bikeway Study (and related)
        - Huron River Greenway Trail (Box 22)
        - Huron River Greenway Planning Report 2000 (Box 22)
        - Huron River Plan 2002 (Box 22)
        - Permit
          - Application 2000-2006 (Box 22)
          - Appeal 2006 (Box 22)
        - Michigan Natural Rivers Report 1977 (Box 22)
        - Huron Valley Corridor Study 1978 (Box 22)
        - Waterworks Master Plan 1986 (Box 22)
        - Proposal for Services -- Huron River Bikeway Study 1983 (Box 22)
        - Proposal for Segment 'D' Nonmotorized Trail 2003 (Box 22)
        - Segment 'D' Nonmotorized Trail Proposal file (Box 22)
        - Huron River Bipath -- Participatory Design 1976 (Box 22)
        - Huron River Bikeway Study 1984 (Box 22)
        - Segment 'D' Summary Report 2004 (Box 22)
        - Segment 'D' Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 22)
        - Prelim Bike Study Report 1997 (Box 22)
        - Public Meetings (Box 22)
        - Correspondence and Meetings, 3 folders (Box 22)
      - Huron -- Whittaker Corridor
        - Fund Applications 1999, 4 folders (Box 23)
        - Huron-Whittaker Corridor Study Proposal 1998 (Box 23)
        - Huron-Whittaker Corridor Study 1999 (Box 23)
        - I-94 Huron Street Interchange Specifications 2000, 2 folders (Box 23)
        - I-94 Huron Street Interchange Landscape Enhancement Plans 2000 (Box 23)
        - TEA-21: North Campus Corridor Non-Motorized Pathway (Box 23)
        - Ypsilanti
          - Project Proposals 1999 (Box 23)
          - Public Meetings 1999-2000, 2 folders (Box 23)
        - Rolled drawings (Box 23)
      - Independence Lake Park
        - Awards 1986 (Box 24)
        - Background (Box 24)
        - Water Spray Play Facility Drawings 2001 (Box 24)
        - Drawings 1981-1982 (Box 24)
        - Phase II
          - Notes (Box 24)
          - Plan Proposals (Box 24)
          - Master Plan (Box 24)
          - Pre-Applications 1978-1986 (Box 24)
          - Graphics (Box 24)
          - Contract (Box 24)
        - Promotional Materials (Box 24)
        - Site location (Box 24)
        - Addendum #1 (Box 24)
        - Correspondence (Box 24)
        - Master Plan (Box 24)
        - Notes (Box 24)
        - Site development plan 1978 (Box 24)
        - Master plan update 2008 (Box 24)
        - DEQ Permit 2001 (Box 24)
        - Miscellaneous 2000 (Box 24)
        - Water Spray Play Facility Construction 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 24)
        - Water Spray Play Facility specifications 2001-2002 (Box 24)
        - Winter Parking Lot and Trails 2002 (Box 24)
        - Winter Parking Lot and Trails Permits (Box 24)
        - Workshop Notes, 22 May 2000 (Box 24)
        - Tree planting specifications 1988 (Box 24)
        - Request for Proposal 2003 (Box 24)
        - Park development proposal 2000 (Box 24)
      - Pere Marquette Rail-Trail of Mid-Michigan (Midland County, Mich.)
        - Arbutus Bog signs 1998 (Box 25)
        - ASLA Awards submission (includes slides) (binder) (Box 25)
        - A Vision for a Linear Park in Midland County 1992 (Box 25)
        - Bike studies 2000 (Box 25)
        - Bridge Diagrams (Box 25)
        - Bridge Stuff (Box 25)
        - City of Caseville 1996-1997 (Box 25)
        - Clippings 1994-1996 (Box 25)
        - Connecting Michigan 2000 2000 (Box 25)
        - Grant applications
          - DNR/MDOT for Phase III 1993 (Box 25)
          - ISTEA/MDOT applications 1993 (Box 25)
          - ISTEA 1992 (Box 25)
          - ISTEA applications 1992-1993 (Box 25)
          - ISTEA general materials -- Phase II (Box 25)
        - Midland County Linear Park Proposal for Services 1991 (Box 25)
        - Midland County Parks and Recreation Policies and Procedures 1992 (Box 25)
        - Pere Marquette Rail-Trail: From Start to Finish 2000 (Box 25)
        - Photographs and Negatives (Box 25)
        - Plans
          - Arbutus Bog (Box 25)
          - City of Coleman 1994 (Box 25)
          - Dublin Avenue to Veterans Memorial Park (Box 25)
        - Project development 1994-1999 (Box 25)
        - Surveys
          - Phase II (Box 25)
          - Phase III (Box 25)
          - Phase IV (Box 25)
        - Drawings and Plans (Box 25)
    - Drawings and plans
      - Alpena Bi-Path
        - Potential Alignment May 14, 1975 (Tube 39)
        - Plans June 11, 1975 (Tube 39)
        - Plans May 20, 1975 (Tube 39)
        - Miscellaneous Plans (Tube 39)
        - Plans
          - Preliminary Engineering Report December 3, 2003 (Tube 39)
          - Proposed Phase 1 -- Marine Work November 14, 2005 (Tube 40)
          - Proposed Phase 2 -- Floating Pier System November 9, 2005 (Tube 41)
        - Miscellaneous sketches (Tube 41)
        - Miscellaneous sketches (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
      - Cherry Hill (Superior Township) -- Sketches and Overlays (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
      - Independence Lake Park
        - Miscellaneous Drawings and Sketches (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
        - Concept Sketches January 13, 1978 (Tube 1)
        - Plans
          - Water Spray Play Feature -- Issued for Construction March 15, 2001 (Tube 43)
          - Boardwalks and Culvert Replacement -- Inland Lakes and Streams Permit November 10, 2000 (Tube 43)
          - Site Construction March 7, 1988 (Tube 43)
          - Parking Lot and Trails -- Issued for Construction October 13, 2000 (Tube 44)
          - Plans February 21, 1979 (Tube 44)
        - Presentation Drawings and Notes (Tube 3)
      - Pere Marquette Rail Trail (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
        - City Midland -- Miscellaneous Sketches and Drawings 1992 (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
        - Currie Parkway Crossing Options June 1992 (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
        - Seating Area Locations June 1992 (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
        - City Midland -- Miscellaneous Sketches and Drawings 1992 (Tube 46)
        - City of Coleman -- Miscellaneous Sketches and Drawings (Tube 46)
        - Sanford Lake Park -- Miscellaneous Plans and Sketches (Tube 47)
        - Overview (Tube 47)
        - Miscellaneous Plans and Sketches (Tube 47)
        - Plans (Tube 48)
          - Arbutus Bog Boardwalk April 3, 1995 (Tube 48)
          - City of Coleman July 13, 1994 (Tube 48)
          - City of Coleman Trailhead September 9, 1997 (Tube 48)
          - City of Midland Section July 31, 1992 (Tube 49)
          - City of Midland Section -- Supplementary Path Information August 14, 1992 (Tube 49)
          - Dublin Ave (Midland, MI) to Cedar St (Sanford, MI) September 10, 1993 (Tube 49)
          - Dublin Ave (Midland, MI) to North Bradley (Geneva Township, MI) July 8, 1994 (Tube 50)
          - Dublin Ave (Midland, MI) to North Bradley (Geneva Township, MI) -- Sanford Village Restroom Building June 28, 1996 (Tube 50)
          - Dublin Ave (Midland, MI) to Veterans Memorial Park (Jerome Township, MI) December 15, 1998 (Tube 51)
          - North Bradley (Geneva Township, MI) to Coleman City Limits (Coleman, MI) September 26, 1994 (Tube 51)
          - Rail Trail Amenities June 15, 1998 (Tube 51)
- Teaching Files and Other Activities
  Teaching Files and Other Activities (2.5 linear feet) document Pollack's involvement with the Natural Areas Technical Advisory Committee (NATAC), his work at the University of Michigan, and various professional activities. Items include minutes, correspondence, course materials, and award applications.
  - Teaching Files
    - American Society of Landscape Architects' (ASLA) Annual Meeting 2005 (Box 26)
    - Certified Hazardous Materials Managers Conference 2001 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence
      - Ann Arbor development 2003-2005 (Box 26)
      - General 2000-2005, 3 folders (Box 26)
    - Detroit Charrette 2001-2002 (Box 26)
    - Full professor application 1996-1997 (Box 26)
    - Landscape Architecture -- 100th Anniversary 2007-2008 (Box 26)
    - Landscape Architecture appointment 2007 (Box 26)
    - Landscape Architecture faculty 2001-2002 (Box 26)
    - Landscape Architecture re-accreditation 2008 (Box 26)
    - Pollack Design Associates 1993 (Box 26)
    - School of Natural Resources 587
      - Course materials 1998-2000, 3 folders (Box 26)
      - Correspondence 2000 (Box 26)
    - School of Natural Resources 590 -- Course Materials 1999 (Box 26)
    - School of Natural Resources 791
      - Course materials 2001 (Box 26)
      - Correspondence 2000-2001 (Box 26)
    - School of Natural Resources 688
      - Course Materials 1998-2002, 2 folders (Box 26)
      - Project proposals 1990-1998 (Box 26)
    - School of Natural Resources Landscape Architecture Faculty Retreat 2001 (Box 26)
    - Senior Graduation talk 2005 (Box 26)
    - Teaching evaluations 2000-2001 (Box 26)
    - Tour de Wetlands 2002 (Box 26)
    - Urban Planning 505 2001 (Box 26)
  - Natural Areas Technical Advisory Committee (NATAC)
    - Purchasing Cycles
      - Rounds 1 and 2 (Box 26)
      - Round 3 (Box 26)
      - Round 4 (Box 26)
      - Round 7 (Box 26)
    - Meetings and Correspondence
      - 2001-2002 (Box 26)
      - 2002 (Box 27)
      - 2003-2004 (Box 27)
      - 2005, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - 2006 (Box 27)
      - 2007 (Box 27)
      - 2008 (Box 27)
      - 2009 (Box 27)
      - 2009-2010 (Box 27)
    - Greenbelt Advisory Commission (Box 27)
    - Open Space Visioning Workshop 2005 (Box 27)
    - Public Access Materials (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous
    - ASLA Call for Proposals 1995 (Box 27)
    - ASLA Community Service Award (Box 27)
    - ASLA Council on Education, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Clippings (Box 27)
    - Design Michigan: Alpena Bipath (Box 27)
    - FASLA Nomination Forms (Box 27)
    - Landscape Architecture Accreditation Board, 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Landscape Architecture Body of Knowledge, 3 folders (Box 28)
    - Michigan Society of Planning Officials Award Application -- Ann Arbor Plan for Parks, Recreation and Open Space 1982 (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 28)
  - Collected Material
    - The 28th Street Study 1982 (Box 28)
    - Collected Design Guidelines, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Dayton Climate Project Working Papers 1981 (Box 28)
    - Dayton Urban Design 1981 (Box 28)
    - Michigan Department of State and Highways Pamphlet 1970 (Box 28)
    - Mills/Hoyt Preservation Program 1982 (Box 28)
    - Near Northeast Neighborhood News -- Ann Arbor (Box 28)
    - Project Grow Newsletter 2005-2006 (Box 28)
    - School of Natural Resources Michigan Workshop 1976 (Box 28)
    - Treyburn, NC Design Guidelines 1986 (Box 28)
- Videotapes
  The Videotapes (1 linear foot) series is comprised of VHS tapes that document the State Street Urban Design Project and various areas of Ann Arbor.
  - State Street Urban Design Project Construction Videos, VHS
    - Drainage estimates 2002 (Box 29)
    - E. Liberty 2002, 2 tapes (Box 29)
    - E. Liberty and State 2002 (Box 29)
    - Maynard 2002, 2 tapes (Box 29)
    - Maynard and E. Williams 2002 (Box 29)
    - S. State, William, and University 2002 (Box 29)
    - Thayer and William 2002 (Box 29)
    - Thompson and Washington 2002 (Box 29)
    - Washington, Liberty, and William 2003, 2 tapes (Box 29)
    - William, Thompson, and Thayer 2003, 2 tapes (Box 29)
    - William and Thayer 2003, 2 tapes (Box 29)
    - William and Washington 2002 (Box 29)
  - NTSC
    - Ann Arbor Lower Town Area Auto Tour 2002 (Box 29)
    - Ann Arbor Aerial Overview 2002 (Box 29)
    - River Tour 2002 (Box 29)
  - School of Natural Resources (Box 29)
  - Bandemer Park Development Simulations 1990 (Box 29)
- Digital Materials
  The Digital Material series has been arranged in the following sub series: Ann Arbor Projects, Herman Miller Projects, Pfizer Projects, and other Michigan Projects. The series consists of digital material related to a number of Pollack's projects and includes design files, presentations, photographs, and project plans. The digital material came to the library on CD-ROMs, which were then transferred to a computer using the Duke Data Accessioner and uploaded to the University of Michigan's Deep Blue digital repository.
  - Ann Arbor Projects, zip file, 599450Kb
    (zip file includes the following folders)
    - Fuller Road Exhibits 2006
    - Great Street Toolkit
    - Mallets Creek -- Brown Park RFP
  - Herman Miller Projects, zip file, 55243Kb
    - Greenhouse Presentation 2003
    - Images
    - ZMS Master Plan 2005
  - Other Michigan Projects, zip file, 404570Kb
    (zip file includes the following folders and subfolders)
    - Charlevoix Specification Issued for Bidding 2006
    - Huron River Bikeway Study
      - Huron River Bikeway Study General
      - Huron Whittaker Corridor Study Boards
      - Segment D Aerials
      - Segment D Revised Aerial Photographs
      - Segment D Trail Aerial Bases
      - WCPARC Border to Boarder Trail Meeting Materials
    - Sanford Lake Park Site Improvements 2007
  - Pfizer Projects, zip file, 404570Kb
    - 2800 Site B10 entry, 2002
    - Baxter Road Entrance Specifications
    - Huron Parkway Reconstruction
    - Master Plan Framework
    - Planned Unit Development